A Guide to the Episcopal Diocese of Southwestern Virginia 1905-1990
Digital Libraries and Archives, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Digital Libraries and Archives, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Episcopal Diocese of Southwestern Virginia, Papers 1905-1990
Digital Libraries and Archives, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Ms85-004
93.0 cubic feet; 93 boxes
The records were permanently deposited in 1985 by the Episcopal Diocese of Southwestern Virginia.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open to research.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Episcopal Diocese of Southwestern Virginia was originally formed from the Diocese of Virginia, which was organized in 1795 and included the area that is now the states of Virginia and West Virginia. West Virginia achieved its statehood in 1863, and split from the Diocese in 1877. In 1892 the Diocese of Southern Virginia was formed, and in 1919 the western part of the diocese split off to form the Episcopal Diocese of Southwestern Virginia. Robert Carter Jett, D.D., of the Virginia Episcopal School, was consecrated Bishop of the Diocese in March 1920. He selected Roanoke as the headquarters, and St. John's for his parish church. Bishop Jett established a diocesan newsletter, encouraged interdenominational cooperation among the Protestant sects, and oversaw a program of church construction and the growth of mission schools. In 1938 Bishop Jett retired and Henry Disbrow Phillips assumed the duties of Bishop of the Diocese. Under Phillips' leadership, the Diocese continued to expand in parishioners and influence, most notably in the growth in the Diocese's function in education. William Henry Marmion became the third Bishop of Southwestern Virginia in May 1954, and led the Diocese through an era of social upheaval in the 1960s. Bishop Marmion was strongly against racial segregation, and was confronted with the problem of challenging the long-held beliefs of many of his parishioners while integrating blacks into the church at the same time. The 1960s and 1970s also saw women pushing for a higher status in society, and the Diocese saw women increasingly become part of the church leadership as lay readers, deacons, and priests. Bishop Marmion also guided his parish into accepting the revisions of the Book of Common Prayer. Bishop Marmion retired in 1979, and Bishop Heath Light assumed leadership that same year. See Hills of the Lord: the Background of the Episcopal Church in Southwestern Virginia, 1738-1938 by Katherine L. Brown (1979) for more information on the early history of the Diocese.
Scope and Content Information
The records of the Diocese consist of the Diocese's administrative records, including incoming (often from parishioners) and outgoing correspondence, with a scattering of newspaper clippings, photographs, building plans and surveys, pamphlets, and meeting minutes, from the central administrative office in Roanoke and the churches within the Diocese. The materials are organized in rough chronological order from 1905 to 1984. The original numbering system used in the Bishop's office is noted in the container list following with a number the year the material was created. For example, (1921:309) indicates that the material in the Folder dates from 1921 and that the Folder was originally numbered 309. That numbering system was organized with participating Episcopal parishes listed alphabetically, followed by subjects, within each year. Not every year has materials from each parish or about each subject.
Arrangement
Documents are arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Box 1, 1905-1922
- Evington--Good Shepherd 1905 (Box-folder 1-1)
- Council--minutes and papers (319) 1919 (Box-folder 1-2)
- Episcopal Residence Committee (315) 1919-20 (Box-folder 1-3)
- Council--minutes and papers (319) 1919-20 (Box-folder 1-4)
- First Annual Council (335); Constitution and canons (336) 1919-20 (Box-folder 1-5)
- Lantern Slides 1920 (Box-folder 1-6)
- Staunton--Trinity Church--consecration of Reverend Robert Carter Jett, D.D., Bishop-Elect 1920 (Box-folder 1-7)
- Byllesby (25); St. Peter's-in-the-mountains--Callaway (33) 1920, 1921-22 (Box-folder 1-8)
- Grace--Glade Spring (75); Christ--Gladys (76); St. John's--Gladys (77) 1922, 1920, 1921-22 (Box-folder 1-9)
- Correspondence (317) 1920-21 (Box-folder 1-10)
- Church Pension Fund (318) 1920-21 (Box-folder 1-11)
- St. Thomas'--Christiansburg (36); Ivy Chapel--Coffee (41) 1922, 1920-21 (Box-folder 1-12)
- Emmanuel--Merrimac Mines (125); St. Mark's-- Montvale (126) 1920-21 (Box-folder 1-13)
- St. John's Chapel--Wytheville (221) 1920-21 (Box-folder 1-14)
- C. Edwin Michael--Treasurer (302) 1920-21 (Box-folder 1-15)
- Virginia Episcopal School (305) 1920-21 (Box-folder 1-16)
- G.W. Ribble--Diocesan Record--Southwestern Episcopalian (313) 1920-21 (Box-folder 1-17)
- Reverend Claudius F. Smith--Diocesan Missioner (321) 1920-21 (Box-folder 1-18)
- Interchurch World Movement (342); Church supplies (343) 1920-21 (Box-folder 1-19)
- Sunday School Institutes (349); Second Annual Council (350) 1920-21 (Box-folder 1-20)
- Bishop's Discretionary Fund (360) 1920-21 (Box-folder 1-21)
- E; F 1920-22 (Box-folder 1-22)
- Province of Washington (345); Province of Washington--Educational Department (345A) 1920-22 (Box-folder 1-23)
- Consecration of Bishops (358); Brotherhood of St. Andrew (359) 1920-22 (Box-folder 1-24)
- Unused stationary of Reverend William Byrd Lee, Jr. of Christ--Blacksburg 1921 (Box-folder 1-25)
- H; Inter-Racial Conference--Richmond, Virginia 1921 (Box-folder 1-26)
- Dewitt, J. Thomas 1921 (Box-folder 1-27)
- Circulars to clergy and parish officers 1921 (Box-folder 1-28)
- Fieldale (123A); Grace--Massie's Mills (124) 1921-22 (Box-folder 1-29)
- Mission--Pounding Mill (149); Christ--Pulaski (150) 1921-22 (Box-folder 1-30)
- St. Peter's--Roanoke (159); St. Luke's--Roanoke (Race relations, 160) 1921, 1922 (Box-folder 1-31)
- Executive Board meeting--(308A) September 13, 1921 (Box-folder 1-32)
- Executive Board meeting--(308B) October 21, 1921 (Box-folder 1-33)
- Executive Board meeting--(308C) December 9, 1921 (Box-folder 1-34)
- Presiding Bishop and Council (344) 1921 (Box-folder 1-35)
- Presiding Bishop and Council--Missionary centennial (344A) 1921 (Box-folder 1-36)
- Province of Washington--Delegates to Synod; Committee on schools and college (344B) 1921 (Box-folder 1-37)
- Journal of Council--Original parish reports (350A) 1921 (Box-folder 1-38)
- Council--Parish reports: typewriter (350B) 1921 (Box-folder 1-39)
- Second Annual Council--supplementary vestries (350C) 1921 (Box-folder 1-40)
- In addition to the items listed above, this box also contains several large, rolled photographs of the Boys Home in Covington.
- Box 2 1921-23
- Church pension fund; monthly arrearages in diocese 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-1)
- B 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-2)
- Burnz, Edgar C., Reverend 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-3)
- D; Domestic and Foreign Missionary Society 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-4)
- G 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-5)
- L; Logan, Mercer P., Reverend 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-6)
- M; N; Nelson, Thomas K., D.D. 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-7)
- Q; Roberts, Albert N. 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-8)
- W; Whitlock, Bernard 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-9)
- St. John's-in-the-mountains--Endicott 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-10)
- St. Thomas's--Abingdon (1); Good Shepherd--Abingdon (2) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-11)
- St. Peter's--Altavista (3); Amherst--Altavista (4) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-12)
- St. Phillip's--Bedford (Race relations, 17) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-13)
- St. Thomas' (Sedalia)--Big Island (19); Christ--Big Stone Gap (20) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-14)
- Christ--Blacksburg (21); Emmanuel--Bristol (22) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-15)
- Brookneal (22 1/2); Trinity--Buchanan (23); Christ-- Buena Vista (24) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-16)
- Good Shepherd--Evington (63); St. Mark's--Fincastle (69) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-17)
- St. John's--Glasgow (78); St. Mary's--Graham (79) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-18)
- St. Luke's--Hot Springs (86) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-19)
- St. Andrew's--Ivanhoe (93) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-20)
- St. Andrew's--Keokee (101); R.E. Lee Memorial--Lexington (108) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-21)
- St. Paul's--Lynchburg (113) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-22)
- Trinity--Lynchburg Route #4:(Boonesboro, Bedford County, 115); Emmanuel--Madison Heights (121) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-23)
- Christ--Marion (122); Christ--Martinsville (123) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-24)
- Grace--Natural Bridge (Purgatory Mountain, Botetourt County, 135); Trinity--Natural Bridge Station (136); Mission--Nora (137) 1921-23, n.d. (Box-folder 2-25)
- All Saint's--Norton (139) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-26)
- St. Luke's--Pedlar Mills (147) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-27)
- Grace--Radford (156); Christ--Roanoke (157) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-28)
- St. John's--Roanoke (158) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-29)
- Trinity--Rocky Mount (176) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-30)
- Trinity--Rustburg (179); Sandy Ridge Mission--St. Paul, RFD #1 (186) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-31)
- St. Paul's--Saltville (189); Christ Mission-- Schuyler (191) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-32)
- Grace--(Mt. Athos), Six Mile Bridge (192); Emmanuel--Staunton (193) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-33)
- Christ--Warm Springs (216) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-34)
- St. John's--Waynesboro (217) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-35)
- Piney--St. Barnabas (222) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-36)
- Bishop Jett: correspondence with him during vacation in February 1922 (300A); Bishop Jett's pastoral letters and similar papers (300B) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-37)
- Craighill, F.H., Reverend--Secretary (: 301); Industrial School (for) Homeless Boys (304) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-38)
- Virginia Episcopal School (305) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-39)
- St. Luke's Church--Norfolk (306); Rich, E.A., Reverend--Archdeaconry matters (307) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-40)
- Archdeaconry: orphanage and school (307A); Possible successors to Rev. E.A. Rich (307B) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-41)
- Standing Committee (309); Tucker, Beverly D., Reverend (311); Thomson, A.C., Reverend (312) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-42)
- Tyler, W.D. (314); Episcopal Residence Committee (315); Trustees--Diocese of Southwestern Virginia (317) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-43)
- Episcopal Residence Committee (315) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-44)
- Church pension fund (318) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-45)
- Council--minutes and papers (319) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-46)
- Committee on Missions (320); Stewardship literature series (320A); Committee on Social Services (321); Committee on Religious Education (322) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-47)
- Committee on Religous Education (322A); Gibson, Churchill J., Reverend (325); Hobart, Mrs. T.D. (326?); Davis, Miss Aurelia (327); Mingea, Mrs. W.E. (328) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-48)
- Michael, C. Edwin (329); Clergy supply (331) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-49)
- Railroads (337) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-50)
- Office supplies (339) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-51)
- Telephone and telegraph (339A); New River Convocation (341) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-52)
- Women's Auxiliary (347); NWC--1920 follow-up (348); NWC--1921 follow-up (348A) 1921-22 (Box-folder 2-53)
- Box 3 1921-23
- Southwest Episcopalian (351) 1921-22 (Box-folder 3-1)
- Southwest Episcopalian--lists for (351A);Parish lists-- copied (351B) 1921-22 (Box-folder 3-2)
- Examining chaplains (352); Postulants (353); Diocesan Missioner (354) 1921-22 (Box-folder 3-3)
- Mingea, W.E. 1921-23 (Box-folder 3-4)
- P; Parochial reports 1921-23 (Box-folder 3-5)
- Patton, J. Lindsay, Jr. 1921-23 (Box-folder 3-6)
- Theological Seminary of Virginia--Alexandria 1921-23 (Box-folder 3-7)
- Williams, George Cleveland 1921-23 (Box-folder 3-8)
- St. John's--Wytheville (220) 1921-23 (Box-folder 3-9)
- Right Reverend R.C. Jett, Bishop (300) 1921-23 (Box-folder 3-10)
- A; Ambler, J. Jacquelin, Jr. 1922 (Box-folder 3-11)
- Beard, William K.; Board of Church Finance 1922 (Box-folder 3-12)
- C 1922 (Box-folder 3-13)
- Forbes, J. Henry 1922 (Box-folder 3-14)
- Rev. Charles Stuart Hale; R. Irvine Hawley; Rev. Thomas Howell 1922 (Box-folder 3-15)
- I; J; K; 1922 (Box-folder 3-16)
- M 1922 (Box-folder 3-17)
- O; Open and Free Church Association 1922 (Box-folder 3-18)
- Church pageantry 1922 (Box-folder 3-19)
- Roanoke: Raleigh Court Proposition (Box-folder 3-20)
- R; S 1922 (Box-folder 3-21)
- T; U; Vestries 1922 (Box-folder 3-22)
- Major Roy W. Wonson 1922 (Box-folder 3-23)
- Y; Z 1922 (Box-folder 3-24)
- Christ (Indian)--Amherst (5); Arrington (6) 1922 (Box-folder 3-25)
- St. Mary's--Basic (15); St. John's--Bedford (6) 1922 (Box-folder 3-26)
- Emmanuel--Covington (42); St. Mark's--Dante (53) 1922 (Box-folder 3-27)
- Christ--Gladys (76) 1922 (Box-folder 3-28)
- Epiphany--Lynchburg (110); Grace Memorial--Lynchburg (111) 1922 (Box-folder 3-29)
- St. John's--Lynchburg (112) 1922 (Box-folder 3-30)
- Good Shepherd (Race Relations)--Lynchburg (114) 1922 (Box-folder 3-31)
- St. Paul's Mission--Nemours, West Virginia (Flat Top Yards, Virginia, 141); Christ--Pearisburg (146) 1922-23 (Box-folder 3-32)
- St. Paul--RFD, Grace House-on-the-Mountain (186A); St. Paul's--Salem (187) 1922 (Box-folder 3-33)
- Trinity--Staunton (194); Stras Memorial--Tazewell (201) 1922 (Box-folder 3-34)
- Stuart Hall (216) 1922 (Box-folder 3-35)
- C. Edwin Michael, Treasurer (302) 1922 (Box-folder 3-36)
- C. Edwin Michael, Treasurer (302) 1922 (Box-folder 3-37)
- C. Edwin Michael, Treasurer (302) 1922 (Box-folder 3-38)
- Virginia Episcopal School (305) 1922 (Box-folder 3-39)
- Executive Board meeting--(308D) January 20, 1922 (Box-folder 3-40)
- Executive Board meeting--(308E) March 7, 1922 (Box-folder 3-41)
- Executive Board meeting--(308F) March 17, 1922 (Box-folder 3-42)
- Executive Board meeting--(308G) March 21, 1922 (Box-folder 3-43)
- Executive Board (308H); (308I); (308J) April 21, 1922, May 15, 1922, July 7, 1922 (Box-folder 3-44)
- Executive Board meeting--(308K); (308M) August 8, 1922, October 22, 1922 (Box-folder 3-45)
- Executive Board (308M); (308N) November 23, 1922, December 15, 1922 (Box-folder 3-46)
- Council (310A); Council: parish reports (319B) 1922 (Box-folder 3-47)
- Deaconess Blanche Adams Fund (317) 1922 (Box-folder 3-48)
- Council: program (319C); Council: appointments (319D) 1922 (Box-folder 3-49)
- Council: certificates of lay delegates (319E); Layman's meeting (319F); Council: committee on entertainment (319G) 1922 (Box-folder 3-50)
- Sunday School: local; Journal primary council (332) 1922 (Box-folder 3-51)
- Interchurch World Movement (342); Church supplies (1922: 343) 1922 (Box-folder 3-52)
- Presiding Bishop and council: Dept. NWC (344B) 1922 (Box-folder 3-53)
- Presiding Bishop and council: Dept. of Religious Education (344C); Presiding Bishop and council;--Lewis B. Franklin, Treasurer (344D) 1922 (Box-folder 3-54)
- Box 4 1922-24
- Presiding Bishop and council: Department of Missions (344E); Presiding Bishop and Council; Dept. of Publicity (344F); Presiding Bishop and Council; Dept. of Christian Social Service (344G) 1922 (Box-folder 4-1)
- Lay readers (355) 1922 (Box-folder 4-2)
- The Church at Work (357) 1922 (Box-folder 4-3)
- N.W.C. Reports of pledges for 1923: from parishes (387) 1922 (Box-folder 4-4)
- N.W.C. Dept. of Publicity (387L); Charles Francis Cocke, Chancellor (388); Portable chapels, parish houses, etc. (389) 1922 (Box-folder 4-5)
- Library (394); Summer workers--men (395); Summer workers- -women (395A); Sweet Briar College (396) 1922 (Box-folder 4-6)
- Summer School of Religious Education (397) 1922 (Box-folder 4-7)
- Summer School of Religious Education (397) 1922 (Box-folder 4-8)
- Church Congress: Baltimore (398) 1922 (Box-folder 4-9)
- Daughters of the King (399); Virginia Theological Seminary (400); James River Convocation (403); New River Convocation (404) 1922 (Box-folder 4-10)
- Virginia Summer School of Religious Education (405); LIVING CHURCH (407); Stuart Hall (408); Eastern Orthodox and Old Catholic churches (409) 1922 (Box-folder 4-11)
- St. Paul Normal and Industrial School (413); East relief (414) 1922 (Box-folder 4-12)
- St. Paul RFD--Grace House; Copy of deed, plans, and Mr. Tyler's correspondence 1922-23 (Box-folder 4-13)
- Trinity Mission--Richlands (177) 1922-23 (Box-folder 4-14)
- G.W. Ribble: Diocesan Record, S.W. Episcopalian (313) 1922-23 (Box-folder 4-15)
- Correspondence (317) 1922-23 (Box-folder 4-16)
- Correspondence with Mr. A. Brooke Taylor (317) 1922-23 (Box-folder 4-17)
- Church pension fund (318) 1922-23 (Box-folder 4-18)
- Bishop's Discretionary Fund (360) 1922-23 (Box-folder 4-19)
- Church Temperance Society (391); Boy's Conference on Ministry (392); Mailing list--diocesan journals (393) 1922-23 (Box-folder 4-20)
- Beverley M. Boyd 1922-24 (Box-folder 4-21)
- Mosby Montague 1922-24 (Box-folder 4-22)
- Special Committee on Revision of Apportionments 1922-24 (Box-folder 4-23)
- Box 5 1923
- Accountant's Report-- December 31, 1923 (Box-folder 5-1)
- Church Pension Fund 1923 (Box-folder 5-2)
- Committee on clerical support--meeting December 20, 1923 (Box-folder 5-3)
- Council--committee on clerical support 1923 (Box-folder 5-4)
- Council--committee on constitution and canons 1923 (Box-folder 5-5)
- Council--expenses and delegates 1923 (Box-folder 5-6)
- Council--committees on entertainment and arrangements 1923 (Box-folder 5-7)
- Council--credentials of lay delegates 1923 (Box-folder 5-8)
- Council--matters to be brought up 1923 (Box-folder 5-9)
- Council--official "call" and Bishop's letter 1923 (Box-folder 5-10)
- Council--parish reports--correspondence 1923 (Box-folder 5-11)
- Council--committee on program 1923 (Box-folder 5-12)
- Council--committee on church property 1923 (Box-folder 5-13)
- Council--publicity 1923 (Box-folder 5-14)
- Council--committee on the state of the church 1923 (Box-folder 5-15)
- Council--journal, bids, etc. 1923 (Box-folder 5-16)
- Council--journal--Bishop's address 1923 (Box-folder 5-17)
- Council--journal--minutes 1923 (Box-folder 5-18)
- Council--journal, reports of committees, officers, institutions 1923 (Box-folder 5-19)
- Council--journal, resolutions 1923 (Box-folder 5-20)
- Diocesan Summer School--general 1923 (Box-folder 5-21)
- Diocesan Summer School--sundry bills 1923 (Box-folder 5-22)
- Diocesan Summer School--photo orders, impressions, suggestions, etc. 1923 (Box-folder 5-23)
- Diocesan Summer School--registrations 1923 (Box-folder 5-24)
- Diocesan Summer School--transportation and schedules 1923 (Box-folder 5-25)
- Diocesan Summer School--conference on young people's societies 1923 (Box-folder 5-26)
- Executive Board-- March 16, 1923 (Box-folder 5-27)
- Executive Board-- April 20, 1923 (Box-folder 5-28)
- Executive Board-- May 17-18, 1923 (Box-folder 5-29)
- Executive Board-- June 15, 1923 (Box-folder 5-30)
- Executive Board-- July 20, 1923 (Box-folder 5-31)
- Executive Board-- August 17, 1923 (Box-folder 5-32)
- Executive Board-- September 21, 1923 (Box-folder 5-33)
- Executive Board-- October 19, 1923 (Box-folder 5-34)
- Executive Board-- November 16, 1923 (Box-folder 5-35)
- Executive Board-- December 21, 1923 (Box-folder 5-36)
- Field Department--meetings, clergymen-- September 19, 1923 (Box-folder 5-37)
- Field Department--forms for permanent reference 1923 (Box-folder 5-38)
- Field Department--letters written for Mrs. Jett 1923 (Box-folder 5-39)
- Field Department--literature 1923 (Box-folder 5-40)
- Field Department--"The Story of the Program" 1923 (Box-folder 5-41)
- Field Department--reports on canvass in 1923 n.d. (Box-folder 5-42)
- Field Department--Rev. G.O. Mead, Chairman 1923 (Box-folder 5-43)
- Field Department--speakers 1923 (Box-folder 5-44)
- Field Department--meetings--September 20--vestrymen of diocese 1923 (Box-folder 5-45)
- Free and Open Church Association 1923 (Box-folder 5-46)
- Correspondence F-H 1923 (Box-folder 5-47)
- Box 6 1923-24
- Reverend Robert A. Goodwin 1923 (Box-folder 6-1)
- Historical Data--Diocese of Southwestern Virginia 1923 (Box-folder 6-2)
- Ivanhoe--St. Barnabas 1923 (Box-folder 6-3)
- Japan Relief 1923 (Box-folder 6-4)
- National Council--Field Department--"The Program Presented" 1923 (Box-folder 6-5)
- National Council--Field Department 1923 (Box-folder 6-6)
- National Council--Lewis B. Franklin, Treasurer 1923 (Box-folder 6-7)
- Parochial Reports 1923 (Box-folder 6-8)
- Sheerin, Chas. W. 1923 (Box-folder 6-9)
- Provincial Synod 1923 (Box-folder 6-10)
- Sunday School lists 1923 (Box-folder 6-11)
- Vestries June 1, 1923 (Box-folder 6-12)
- Vestries June 1, 1923 (Box-folder 6-13)
- V.E.S.--Bishop's Statement-- March 20 1923 (Box-folder 6-14)
- Charles B. Mitchell (148) 1923 (Box-folder 6-15)
- Episcopal High School (156) 1923 (Box-folder 6-16)
- Executive Board--(308-O) January 19, 1923 (Box-folder 6-17)
- Executive Board--(308-P) February 16, 1923 (Box-folder 6-18)
- A 1923-24 (Box-folder 6-19)
- Abingdon--Good Shepherd "The Knobs"; Abingdon--St. Thomas'; Appalachia Mission 1923-24 (Box-folder 6-20)
- Deaconess Blanche Adams Estate 1923-24 (Box-folder 6-21)
- Altavista--(near) St. Andrew's Mission; Altavista--St. Peter's; Amherst (RFD)--Christ; Bear Mountain (Indian) Mission 1923-24 (Box-folder 6-22)
- Ambler, Jacquelin Jr. 1923-24 (Box-folder 6-23)
- American Church Building Fund Commission; Associate Missions General 1923-24 (Box-folder 6-24)
- Arlington--Trinity; Amherst--Ascension; Basic--St. Mary's 1923-24 (Box-folder 6-25)
- B 1923-24 (Box-folder 6-26)
- Bedford--St. John's 1923-24 (Box-folder 6-27)
- Virginia Episcopal School--financial records 1923-24 (Box-folder 6-28)
- Big Stone Gap--Christ Church 1923-24 (Box-folder 6-29)
- Blacksburg--Christ Church 1923-24 (Box-folder 6-30)
- Board of Church Finance, 289 Fourth Ave., New York 1923-24 (Box-folder 6-31)
- Bristol--Emmanuel 1923-24 (Box-folder 6-32)
- Brookewood Mission; Brookneal--Mission 1923-24 (Box-folder 6-33)
- Buchanan RFD--Grace (Pugatory Mountain); Buchanan-Trinity; Buena Vista--Christ Church 1923-24 (Box-folder 6-34)
- Bullesby Mission; Callaway--St. Peter's-in-the-mountains; Carbo--Mission 1923-24 (Box-folder 6-35)
- Checks; Church at Work 1923-24 (Box-folder 6-36)
- Church Pension Fund 1923-24 (Box-folder 6-37)
- Church Pension Fund--monthly arrearages in diocese 1923-24 (Box-folder 6-38)
- Church Service League or Church School League 1923-24 (Box-folder 6-39)
- Box 7 1923-24
- General correspondence--C 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-1)
- General correspondence--C 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-2)
- Circular letters 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-3)
- Circular letters 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-4)
- Clifford--St. Mark's; Clifton Forge--St. Andrew's 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-5)
- Clinchoe--Mission; Coffee--Ivy Chapel; Covington--Emmanuel 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-6)
- Covington--Grace Mission (Home for Boys); Dante-- St. Mark's 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-7)
- C and D; 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-8)
- D 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-9)
- D 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-10)
- Drill--Mission; Eagle Rock--Emmanuel; Endicott--St. John's-in-the-mountains 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-11)
- E 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-12)
- Endicott--St. John's-in-the-mountains 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-13)
- Endicott--St. John's-in-the-mountains, Mrs. Alice E. Smith correspondence; Evington--Good Shepherd; Evington (RFD)--Church of Our Savior 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-14)
- Executive Board 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-15)
- Field Department of Diocese of Southwest Virginia 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-16)
- Field Department District Chairman 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-17)
- Fincastle--St. Mark's; Forest Depot--St. Stephen's; Glade Springs--Grace 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-18)
- General correspondence--G 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-19)
- General correspondence--G 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-20)
- Gladys--Christ; Glasgow--St. John's; Graham--St. Mark's 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-21)
- Correspondence--G & H 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-22)
- Home for Homeless Boys--Covington 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-23)
- H; I; J 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-24)
- Ivanhoe--St. Barnabas' (Piney); Lebanon--Mission; Lexington--R.E. Lee Memorial 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-25)
- Correspondence J and K; (307) 1923-24 (Box-folder 7-26)